I'll share with you another example and
this is one of my favorites that we
talked about in the book of Daniel
Wright talking about finding Christ
mm-hmm I just want to really just run
through the whole book of Daniel really
quickly and you guys should so and we're
just going to run through this very
quickly so in Daniel 1 we have Daniel
who the Bible says was was without fault
without blame he enters into the kingdom
of Babylon you know he's taken as a
captive even though he was blameless
he's taken as a captain with his people
in order to get to Babylon he has to
cross the river Euphrates so I want you
to imagine Daniel 1 begins with what
Daniel crossing the river Euphrates
almost like this was a baptism into a
new experience for him mm-hmm now the
first thing that happens in Daniel 1 is
he is tented over appetite right so
here's my question for you did Jesus
come to a world where he was guiltless
but came to be a prisoner with his
brothers and sisters with humanity yes
he have a baptism at the Jordan yes and
what was his first temptation appetite
Daniel 1 appetite Jesus presentation
appetite in Daniel chapter 2 we just
discussed there was an image there's an
image of a man who represents these
kingdoms why does this man fall he falls
right and why does he fall because of
pride and I goes before destruction and
a haughty spirit before fall these
kingdom exalted themselves they end up
falling how are they destroyed I stone
being dashed against before me right the
feet right yeah so Satan knows when
Jesus comes he knows this is the stone
that's supposed to destroy my kingdoms
so what does he do second temptation hey
here we have Jesus who represents the
kingdom of heaven what does he say to
him he's like hey if you're the Son of
God why don't you why don't you fall
why don't you throw yourself down don't
worry you will not - your foot - your
foot against the stone wow he's trying
to do - Jesus what was done to the image
yeah Daniel one first impatient Daniel -
second temptation Jesus is first and
Tatian second temptation Daniel Chapter
three
Amy just set up Shadrach Meshach
Abednego bow down and worship this image
what was Jesus at Jesus's third
sensation bow down and worship Daniel
one two and three reflect the beginning
of Christ's ministry his first three
temptations what about Daniel chapter
four Daniel chapter 4 is
Nebuchadnezzar's dream of that great big
tree which represented his kingdom and
the tree was cut down and remember the
language that was used right this tree
its branches lodged in the air and all
the birds came and lodged where the
branches reached out to the air all the
birds came and lodged in this tree it
was so great but God is telling
Nebuchadnezzar your tree this tree
Babylon representing Babylon your
kingdom is not the tree that's going to
last forever
there's another Kingdom represented by
another tree that is the one that's
going to last forever and when Jesus
comes on the scene Jesus gives us
parable the kingdom of God is like and
it's almost as if he's quoting
Nebuchadnezzar's tree the kingdom of
heaven is like a tree I see that when
planted in the ground becomes the
greatest tree and all the birds of the
air knowing that beacon eyes are not
your tree the tree of Calvary that's the
tree that set up the eternal kingdom of
God that's the tree we come to to have
life that's the tree that provides shade
and covering for those who want
salvation so Daniel chapter 4 points to
the death of Christ on Calvary alright
Daniel chapter 5 Daniel chapter 5 you
remember what happened in Daniel chapter
5 riding on the wall
any minute to kill you you Farson your
kingdom is numbered and finished your
Kingdom is numbered and finished why was
it finished because Cyrus who is a type
of Christ is outside the city gates
the Bible says prophesied that he would
dry up the riverbed the river Euphrates
descending to the deep that's what the
Bible calls it the deep and he would
open the gates to set the captives free
well guess what when Jesus was dying on
a cross where was he dying outside the
city of Jerusalem yeah what did he do in
his death he descended hmm into the deep
to open the gates of death and hell in
order to set the captives free
Daniel chapter 4 Christ's death Daniel
chapter 5 Christ's burial and then and
then Daniel chapter 6
mm-hm and what do we have happening in
Daniel chapter 6 Daniel in the lion's
den with a stone over the mouth of that
den and the stone is sealed right make
sure he doesn't come up out of that out
of that that tomb that Tara yeah Daniel
one two three at the beginning of
Christ's ministry Daniel four five six
his death burial and resurrection who
would have thought that Daniel chapters
one through six in another dimension
reflects the story of Jesus Christ right
right and it doesn't stop there because
in Daniel 7 you have Jesus as high
priest hmm so what you have happening
Daniel 7 or Daniel 1 through 6 Christ's
ministry on earth Daniel 7 Jesus is high
priest Daniel 8 Jesus cleansing the
sanctuary Daniel 9 is a prophecy about
the close of probation Daniel 10 11 and
12 Michael stands up to deliver his
people this is photo theology this is
studying the Bible using pictures and
images everyone can understand pictures
yeah you don't have to be a scholar to
understand pictures you don't have to
have a degree to understand pictures
like you know I believe that God is
wanting all of his people
to have this understanding of the
Scriptures because we're limiting God
and we're limiting the scriptures you
know we we kind of hover around the
Sabbath is this day and not this day so
let me prove that and you know we kind
of people are like oh we don't but can
you imagine having a Bible study with
your fellow you know Christian from
other places or other denominations
people who may not even be familiar with
the Bible and just share with them
look at this did you did you know that
Jesus was in the story of Solomon or
David and and and Bathsheba did you know
that Jesus was in this story of and let
me tell you when people begin to see to
see this kind of wall Oh tell me more
there's more to come but let's just
let's just keep look you begin to have
an avenue that I think is so
unintentional but in a sense it's the
very gospel it's the three angels
messages it's everything but it's just
in story format yeah people sitting like
how in the world I could never saw that
before yeah and that's what gets people
excited yeah because now you begin to
see Jesus in the stories of the Bible
yeah